A new era must commence
Bionicle: The Legend Reborn is a action, adventure,
animation film directed by Mark Baldo.
Once the ruler of an entire universe, the Great Spirit Mata Nui finds himself cast out of his own
body, his spirit trapped inside the fabled Mask of Life, hurtling through space.
After landing on the far-away planet of Bara Magna, the mask creates a new body for Mata Nui, who
unwillingly gets caught up in the furious battles of the nearly barren and dangerous planet.
Skrall / Bone Hunters / Vorox (voice), played by Dee Bradley Baker.
Strakk / Tarix (voice), played by Jeff Bennett.
Ackar (voice), played by Jim Cummings.
Mata Nui (voice), played by Michael Dorn.
Gresh (voice), played by Mark Famiglietti.
Metus (voice), played by David Leisure.
Bionicle: The Legend Reborn is a 2009 animated science fantasy
action film based on the Bionicle toy line by Lego.
It is the fourth and final Bionicle film to be released.
Distributed by Universal Studios Home Entertainment, the film is a stand-alone sequel to the trilogy of
films released by Buena Vista Home Entertainment under the Miramax Home Entertainment label.
It follows the toy line's 2009 story and features a different set
of characters than that of the first three films.
The Legend Reborn was released on September 15, 2009, in the United States and
Canada, October 5 in the United Kingdom, and September 2 in Australia.
The film stars Michael Dorn as the voice of Mata Nui.
The Legend Reborn was intended to be the start of a trilogy of films, but production on the
sequels was cancelled due to Lego discontinuing the release of Bionicle toys in 2010.
The story was concluded through other media outlets, including comic
books and a web story titled the "Mata Nui Saga".
The tone is thought_provoking.